Alison Altomari

3823 Sunset Drive Los Angeles, CA 90027 (609) 306-1571 Altomari.Alison@gmail.com www.alaalison.com

Merging my rich experience in marketing with my unparalleled passion for food and agriculture, I excel at working directly with producers and purveyors to build successful brands and connecting the dots between consumers and real food.

Professional Experience

Wonder Valley Olive Oil

Owner

Los Angeles, CA January 2014 - Present

Formulated the proprietary blend for Wonder Valley, an extra virgin olive oil from hand harvested Northern California olives; available for sale Dec. 2014

Taking this brand from ideation to execution through progressive branding and packaging design, website creation, sales management (both wholesale and direct to consumer), and developing a growth and sustainability strategy for the company's long term success

Summerland

Head of Community

Los Angeles, CA January 2014 – Present

Increased Summerland's customer base, social media following and brand recognition by launching pop up markets at Heath Ceramics, General Store, Echo Park Craft Fair and dinner series with One Fine Stay, Apartment A & Kitchen Surfing

Lead buyer for all third party marketplace goods and weekly local produce orders and selection at the Wednesday Santa Monica Farmers Market

Produces custom weekly content for website, social media, and customer collateral through recipe development and food photography and styling

California Olive Oil Council

Marketing Director

Berkeley, CA September 2012 – December 2013

Spearheaded the Council's first media dinners in San Francisco, New York and Baltimore; collaborating with reputable chefs to create menus, educating influential media guests and tastemakers, and generating awareness of the California olive oil industry

Strengthened the extra virgin certification program by implementing new evaluation methods for the taste panel and oversaw the certification of 450+ oils, training as a professional taster

Successfully completed redesign of the council's website and logo; transforming the brand image as well as membership communications

Monvinic Restaurant

Stage (Culinary Apprentice)
Barcelona, Spain January – April 2012

Gained an informal education in the Spanish language as well as authentic Catalan cuisine by training under each kitchen station, reporting to the executive chef

Education

Drexel University

Philadelphia, PA

Graduated magna cum laude, June 2010

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration
Marketing Concentration, Communications Minor

Member of the Drexel Pennoni Honors College & Dean's Student Advisory Board

Received the following scholarships and awards for academic excellence: A.J. Drexel, Dean of LeBow, Honors College, Betsy Z. Cohen, and Paul R. Moul Scholarships as well as Dean's Service and Warren Cooper Awards

Computer Skills

Experienced photographer; trained in photo editing with Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop Elements

Proficient in Microsoft Office, website management, and HTML editing

Activities

Freelance writer and photographer

Certified Yoga Alliance Instructor

Model for J. Crew, Mill Mercantile and RTH shop

à la Alison

www.alaalison.com *Owner/Creator*

à la Alison is a food blog; connecting travel storytelling with seasonal, regional recipes

Personal recipe published in Food52's cookbook, Fall 2012

Selected to host a video segment for the 2011 Atlantic City Food & Wine Festival Facilitated the weekly produce orders and selection from 82 local food purveyors, visiting local markets and live seafood auctions

Agency 51 Advertising

Account Executive
Philadelphia, PA June 2010 – January 2012

Consistently achieved quarterly goals and campaign success through measured reach of target audience as well as an increase in clients' customer base and sales

Collaborated with clients to develop and execute integrated creative campaigns for consumer and business-to-business marketing initiatives across print, broadcast, electronic, and collateral media